<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Options on</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/</link><description>Recent content in Options on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>General options</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/general/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/general/</guid><description>-f FORMAT, -r FORMAT, --from=FORMAT, --read=FORMAT Specify input format. FORMAT can be:
::: {#input-formats}
bibtex (BibTeX bibliography) biblatex (BibLaTeX bibliography) commonmark (CommonMark Markdown) commonmark_x (CommonMark Markdown with extensions) creole (Creole 1.0) csljson (CSL JSON bibliography) csv (CSV table) docbook (DocBook) docx (Word docx) dokuwiki (DokuWiki markup) epub (EPUB) fb2 (FictionBook2 e-book) gfm (GitHub-Flavored Markdown), or the deprecated and less accurate markdown_github; use markdown_github only if you need extensions not supported in gfm.</description></item><item><title>Reader options</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/reader/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/reader/</guid><description>--shift-heading-level-by=NUMBER Shift heading levels by a positive or negative integer. For example, with --shift-heading-level-by=-1, level 2 headings become level 1 headings, and level 3 headings become level 2 headings. Headings cannot have a level less than 1, so a heading that would be shifted below level 1 becomes a regular paragraph. Exception: with a shift of -N, a level-N heading at the beginning of the document replaces the metadata title.</description></item><item><title>General writer options</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/writer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/writer/</guid><description>-s, --standalone Produce output with an appropriate header and footer (e.g. a standalone HTML, LaTeX, TEI, or RTF file, not a fragment). This option is set automatically for pdf, epub, epub3, fb2, docx, and odt output. For native output, this option causes metadata to be included; otherwise, metadata is suppressed.
--template=FILE|URL Use the specified file as a custom template for the generated document. Implies --standalone. See [Templates], below, for a description of template syntax.</description></item><item><title>Options affecting specific writers</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/specific-writer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/specific-writer/</guid><description>--self-contained Produce a standalone HTML file with no external dependencies, using data: URIs to incorporate the contents of linked scripts, stylesheets, images, and videos. Implies --standalone. The resulting file should be &amp;ldquo;self-contained,&amp;rdquo; in the sense that it needs no external files and no net access to be displayed properly by a browser. This option works only with HTML output formats, including html4, html5, html+lhs, html5+lhs, s5, slidy, slideous, dzslides, and revealjs.</description></item><item><title>Citation rendering</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/citations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/citations/</guid><description>-C, --citeproc Process the citations in the file, replacing them with rendered citations and adding a bibliography. Citation processing will not take place unless bibliographic data is supplied, either through an external file specified using the --bibliography option or the bibliography field in metadata, or via a references section in metadata containing a list of citations in CSL YAML format with Markdown formatting. The style is controlled by a [CSL] stylesheet specified using the --csl option or the csl field in metadata.</description></item><item><title>Math rendering in HTML</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/maths-html/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/maths-html/</guid><description>The default is to render TeX math as far as possible using Unicode characters. Formulas are put inside a span with class=&amp;quot;math&amp;quot;, so that they may be styled differently from the surrounding text if needed. However, this gives acceptable results only for basic math, usually you will want to use --mathjax or another of the following options.
--mathjax[=URL] Use MathJax to display embedded TeX math in HTML output. TeX math will be put between \(.</description></item><item><title>Options for wrapper scripts</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/wrappers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/options/wrappers/</guid><description>The default is to render TeX math as far as possible using Unicode characters. Formulas are put inside a span with class=&amp;quot;math&amp;quot;, so that they may be styled differently from the surrounding text if needed. However, this gives acceptable results only for basic math, usually you will want to use --mathjax or another of the following options.
--mathjax[=URL] Use MathJax to display embedded TeX math in HTML output. TeX math will be put between \(.</description></item></channel></rss>