<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Citations on</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/</link><description>Recent content in Citations on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to citations</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/intro/</guid><description>When the --citeproc option is used, pandoc can automatically generate citations and a bibliography in a number of styles. Basic usage is
pandoc --citeproc myinput.txt To use this feature, you will need to have
a document containing citations (see [Extension: citations]); a source of bibliographic data: either an external bibliography file or a list of references in the document&amp;rsquo;s YAML metadata optionally, a [CSL] citation style.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/bib-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/bib-data/</guid><description>You can specify an external bibliography using the bibliography metadata field in a YAML metadata section or the --bibliography command line argument. If you want to use multiple bibliography files, you can supply multiple --bibliography arguments or set bibliography metadata field to YAML array. A bibliography may have any of these formats:
Format File extension
BibLaTeX .bib BibTeX .bibtex CSL JSON .json CSL YAML .yaml
Note that .bib can be used with both BibTeX and BibLaTeX files; use the extension .</description></item><item><title>Citation style</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/cite-style/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/cite-style/</guid><description>Citations and references can be formatted using any style supported by the [Citation Style Language], listed in the [Zotero Style Repository]. These files are specified using the --csl option or the csl (or citation-style) metadata field. By default, pandoc will use the [Chicago Manual of Style] author-date format. (You can override this default by copying a CSL style of your choice to default.csl in your user data directory.) The CSL project provides further information on [finding and editing styles].</description></item><item><title>Citation in note styles</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/cite-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/cite-notes/</guid><description>Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s citation processing is designed to allow you to move between author-date, numerical, and note styles without modifying the markdown source. When you&amp;rsquo;re using a note style, avoid inserting footnotes manually. Instead, insert citations just as you would in an author-date style&amp;mdash;for example,
Blah blah [@foo, p. 33]. The footnote will be created automatically. Pandoc will take care of removing the space and moving the note before or after the period, depending on the setting of notes-after-punctuation, as described below in [Other relevant metadata fields].</description></item><item><title>Raw content in a style</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/raw-content/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/raw-content/</guid><description>To include raw content in a prefix, suffix, delimiter, or term, surround it with these tags indicating the format:
{{jats}}&amp;amp;lt;ref&amp;amp;gt;{{/jats}} Without the tags, the string will be interpreted as a string and escaped in the output, rather than being passed through raw.
This feature allows stylesheets to be customized to give different output for different output formats. However, stylesheets customized in this way will not be usable by other CSL implementations.</description></item><item><title>Placement of the bibliography</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/placement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/placement/</guid><description>If the style calls for a list of works cited, it will be placed in a div with id refs, if one exists:
::: {#refs} ::: Otherwise, it will be placed at the end of the document. Generation of the bibliography can be suppressed by setting suppress-bibliography: true in the YAML metadata.
If you wish the bibliography to have a section heading, you can set reference-section-title in the metadata, or put the heading at the beginning of the div with id refs (if you are using it) or at the end of your document:</description></item><item><title>Including uncited items in the bibliography</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/uncited/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/uncited/</guid><description>If you want to include items in the bibliography without actually citing them in the body text, you can define a dummy nocite metadata field and put the citations there:
--- nocite: | @item1, @item2 ... @item3 In this example, the document will contain a citation for item3 only, but the bibliography will contain entries for item1, item2, and item3.
It is possible to create a bibliography with all the citations, whether or not they appear in the document, by using a wildcard:</description></item><item><title>Other relevant metadata fields</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/other/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/citations/other/</guid><description>A few other metadata fields affect bibliography formatting:
link-citations If true, citations will be hyperlinked to the corresponding bibliography entries (for author-date and numerical styles only). lang The lang field will affect how the style is localized, for example in the translation of labels and the use of quotation marks. (For backwards compatibility, locale may be used instead of lang, but this use is deprecated.) notes-after-punctuation If true (the default), pandoc will put footnote citations after following punctuation.</description></item></channel></rss>