<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Templates on</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/</link><description>Recent content in Templates on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Templates</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/templates-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/templates-intro/</guid><description>When the -s/--standalone option is used, pandoc uses a template to add header and footer material that is needed for a self-standing document. To see the default template that is used, just type
pandoc -D *FORMAT* where FORMAT is the name of the output format. A custom template can be specified using the --template option. You can also override the system default templates for a given output format FORMAT by putting a file templates/default.</description></item><item><title>Template syntax</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/syntax/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/syntax/</guid><description>Comments Anything between the sequence $-- and the end of the line will be treated as a comment and omitted from the output.
Delimiters To mark variables and control structures in the template, either $&amp;hellip;$ or ${&amp;hellip;} may be used as delimiters. The styles may also be mixed in the same template, but the opening and closing delimiter must match in each case. The opening delimiter may be followed by one or more spaces or tabs, which will be ignored.</description></item><item><title>Variables</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/variables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/temps/variables/</guid><description>Metadata variables title, author, date allow identification of basic aspects of the document. Included in PDF metadata through LaTeX and ConTeXt. These can be set through a [pandoc title block][Extension: pandoc_title_block], which allows for multiple authors, or through a [YAML metadata block][Extension: yaml_metadata_block]: --- author: - Aristotle - Peter Abelard ... Note that if you just want to set PDF or HTML metadata, without including a title block in the document itself, you can set the title-meta, author-meta, and date-meta variables.</description></item></channel></rss>