<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Extensions on</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/</link><description>Recent content in Extensions on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extensions</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/ext-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/ext-intro/</guid><description>The behavior of some of the readers and writers can be adjusted by enabling or disabling various extensions.
An extension can be enabled by adding +EXTENSION to the format name and disabled by adding -EXTENSION. For example, --from markdown_strict+footnotes is strict Markdown with footnotes enabled, while --from markdown-footnotes-pipe_tables is pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown without footnotes or pipe tables.
The markdown reader and writer make by far the most use of extensions. Extensions only used by them are therefore covered in the section [Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown] below (See [Markdown variants] for commonmark and gfm.</description></item><item><title>Typography</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/typography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/typography/</guid><description>Extension: smart Interpret straight quotes as curly quotes, --- as em-dashes, -- as en-dashes, and ... as ellipses. Nonbreaking spaces are inserted after certain abbreviations, such as &amp;ldquo;Mr.&amp;rdquo;
This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats:
input formats markdown, commonmark, latex, mediawiki, org, rst, twiki output formats markdown, latex, context, rst enabled by default in markdown, latex, context (both input and output) Note: If you are writing Markdown, then the smart extension has the reverse effect: what would have been curly quotes comes out straight.</description></item><item><title>Headings and sections</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/heads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/heads/</guid><description>Extension: auto_identifiers A heading without an explicitly specified identifier will be automatically assigned a unique identifier based on the heading text.
This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats:
input formats markdown, latex, rst, mediawiki, textile output formats markdown, muse enabled by default in markdown, muse The default algorithm used to derive the identifier from the heading text is:
Remove all formatting, links, etc. Remove all footnotes.</description></item><item><title>Math input</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/maths/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/maths/</guid><description>The extensions tex_math_dollars, tex_math_single_backslash, and tex_math_double_backslash are described in the section about Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown.
However, they can also be used with HTML input. This is handy for reading web pages formatted using MathJax, for example.</description></item><item><title>Literate Haskell support</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/haskell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/haskell/</guid><description>Extension: literate_haskell Treat the document as literate Haskell source.
This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats:
input formats markdown, rst, latex output formats markdown, rst, latex, html If you append +lhs (or +literate_haskell) to one of the formats above, pandoc will treat the document as literate Haskell source. This means that
In Markdown input, &amp;ldquo;bird track&amp;rdquo; sections will be parsed as Haskell code rather than block quotations.</description></item><item><title>Raw HTML/TeX</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/raw/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/raw/</guid><description>The following extensions are described in more detail in their respective sections of [Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown]:
raw_html allows HTML elements which are not representable in pandoc&amp;rsquo;s AST to be parsed as raw HTML. By default, this is disabled for HTML input.
raw_tex allows raw LaTeX, TeX, and ConTeXt to be included in a document. This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats (in addition to markdown):</description></item><item><title>Other extensions</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/other/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/ext/other/</guid><description>Extension: empty_paragraphs Allows empty paragraphs. By default empty paragraphs are omitted.
This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats:
input formats docx, html output formats docx, odt, opendocument, html Extension: native_numbering Enables native numbering of figures and tables. Enumeration starts at 1.
This extension can be enabled/disabled for the following formats:
output formats odt, opendocument Extension: xrefs_name Links to headings, figures and tables inside the document are substituted with cross-references that will use the name or caption of the referenced item.</description></item></channel></rss>