<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pandoc's Markdown on</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/</link><description>Recent content in Pandoc's Markdown on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Markdown</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/md-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/md-intro/</guid><description>Pandoc understands an extended and slightly revised version of John Gruber&amp;rsquo;s [Markdown] syntax. This document explains the syntax, noting differences from standard Markdown. Except where noted, these differences can be suppressed by using the markdown_strict format instead of markdown. Extensions can be enabled or disabled to specify the behavior more granularly. They are described in the following. See also [Extensions] above, for extensions that work also on other formats.
Philosophy Markdown is designed to be easy to write, and, even more importantly, easy to read:</description></item><item><title>Paragraphs</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/paragraphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/paragraphs/</guid><description>A paragraph is one or more lines of text followed by one or more blank lines. Newlines are treated as spaces, so you can reflow your paragraphs as you like. If you need a hard line break, put two or more spaces at the end of a line.
Extension: escaped_line_breaks A backslash followed by a newline is also a hard line break. Note: in multiline and grid table cells, this is the only way to create a hard line break, since trailing spaces in the cells are ignored.</description></item><item><title>Headings</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/headings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/headings/</guid><description>There are two kinds of headings: Setext and ATX.
Setext-style headings A setext-style heading is a line of text &amp;ldquo;underlined&amp;rdquo; with a row of = signs (for a level-one heading) or - signs (for a level-two heading):
A level-one heading =================== A level-two heading ------------------- The heading text can contain inline formatting, such as emphasis (see [Inline formatting], below).
ATX-style headings An ATX-style heading consists of one to six # signs and a line of text, optionally followed by any number of # signs.</description></item><item><title>Block quotations</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/block-quotes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/block-quotes/</guid><description>Markdown uses email conventions for quoting blocks of text. A block quotation is one or more paragraphs or other block elements (such as lists or headings), with each line preceded by a &amp;gt; character and an optional space. (The &amp;gt; need not start at the left margin, but it should not be indented more than three spaces.)
&amp;gt; This is a block quote. This &amp;gt; paragraph has two lines. &amp;gt; &amp;gt; 1.</description></item><item><title>Verbatim (code) blocks</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/verbatim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/verbatim/</guid><description>Indented code blocks A block of text indented four spaces (or one tab) is treated as verbatim text: that is, special characters do not trigger special formatting, and all spaces and line breaks are preserved. For example,
if (a &amp;gt; 3) { moveShip(5 * gravity, DOWN); } The initial (four space or one tab) indentation is not considered part of the verbatim text, and is removed in the output.</description></item><item><title>Line blocks</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/line-blocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/line-blocks/</guid><description>Extension: line_blocks A line block is a sequence of lines beginning with a vertical bar (|) followed by a space. The division into lines will be preserved in the output, as will any leading spaces; otherwise, the lines will be formatted as Markdown. This is useful for verse and addresses:
| The limerick packs laughs anatomical | In space that is quite economical. | But the good ones I've seen | So seldom are clean | And the clean ones so seldom are comical | 200 Main St.</description></item><item><title>Lists</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/lists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/lists/</guid><description>Bullet lists A bullet list is a list of bulleted list items. A bulleted list item begins with a bullet (*, +, or -). Here is a simple example:
* one * two * three This will produce a &amp;ldquo;compact&amp;rdquo; list. If you want a &amp;ldquo;loose&amp;rdquo; list, in which each item is formatted as a paragraph, put spaces between the items:
* one * two * three The bullets need not be flush with the left margin; they may be indented one, two, or three spaces.</description></item><item><title>Horizontal rules</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/rules/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/rules/</guid><description>Horizontal rules A line containing a row of three or more *, -, or _ characters (optionally separated by spaces) produces a horizontal rule:
* * * * ---------------</description></item><item><title>Tables</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/tables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/tables/</guid><description>Tables Four kinds of tables may be used. The first three kinds presuppose the use of a fixed-width font, such as Courier. The fourth kind can be used with proportionally spaced fonts, as it does not require lining up columns.
Extension: table_captions A caption may optionally be provided with all 4 kinds of tables (as illustrated in the examples below). A caption is a paragraph beginning with the string Table: (or just :), which will be stripped off.</description></item><item><title>Metadata blocks</title><link>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/metadata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stefanocoretta.github.io/panman/docs/pandoc-markdown/metadata/</guid><description>Extension: pandoc_title_block If the file begins with a title block
% title % author(s) (separated by semicolons) % date it will be parsed as bibliographic information, not regular text. (It will be used, for example, in the title of standalone LaTeX or HTML output.) The block may contain just a title, a title and an author, or all three elements. If you want to include an author but no title, or a title and a date but no author, you need a blank line:</description></item></channel></rss>